lions like their food grilled too I
suppose right yeah they use I think they
use hickory wood to make it really tasty
[Laughter]
that's right they do
um
no no this one species that we have
that doesn't abide by the rules of
nature
is of course the only species that is
actually capable of being creative
or
some other scientists recently said oh
no it was and said Guru said that what
makes humans different is that we have
possibilities
the possibility of overriding Nature and
creating a new way of
living but with that
ironically as soon as we overwrite that
natural cycle in our Creations
um
we also shorten our lifespan
now I'm going to cut to the chase here
it's very very simple and that is
mammals typically live
10 times their sexual maturity age that
means cats start reproducing after 12
months latest right they have their
babies they live 10 years but actually
most cats live 15 to 20 years
so look at all the other mammals um deer
in the wild
again live to 20 years and elephants
live
elephants actually don't live to
10 times their sexual mind you I don't
know what the sexual maturity age is I
should not talk about elephants I only
know that they have the same gestation
period as humans nine months does
anybody know when they become sexually
active now of course also most other
mammals in including that time scale
they grow to full size within their
first year or two right even the big
ones and humans don't humans take
females 12 years for the most part
males over 20 years to grow to their
full physical size but sexual maturity
nevertheless reproductive abilities
starts between 12 and 15 years of age so
what does that mean we should at least
live 120 to 150 years
is that so crazy actually it is not
when you look into the hunza population
in the Himalayan Mountains there was a
whole population that
they say they stayed there from soldiers
left there
um from the wars of Alexander the Great
the Greek guy
and um
they mixed with local people and became
this whole kind of enclosed population
of a few tens of thousands of people
that
um live on guess what
um raw foods they dry their their fruits
and vegetables on large Rock faces for
the winter period of time and they fast
and just drink
um
a juice like a smoothie we would call it
today of dried apricots ground into
water
um Every Spring so that was the old
tradition of course now they've been
what's the word compromised
and
um
and no longer have that clean lifestyle
and they lived on average to 120. many
live to 150 even 160.
and that is documented
journalists went there in the early 80s
and actually you know they hiked up
there into the mountains and reported
that In Those Old articles were visible
a few years ago when the internet first
opened up but have since been
de-platformed I suppose because that's
not the kind of knowledge that Western
medicine would like us to believe right
foreign okay so this was just a very
brief look at the biology of Life on
planet Earth there's another fact like
gravity like Seasons because they're of
the rotation of the planet
um
there's another law on planet Earth that
very few people take note of
and that is that all life lives only in
a particular temperature range
and again that's all life that's not
some
all life on the surface of planet Earth
lives within a particular temperature
range and that is very easy to
understand at what point does Your
Spinach go limped as you seed not
reproduce does your child with a fever
die because the brain gets cooked it's
very easy for humans it's 106 degrees
and for most other life it's maximum 120
degrees
end of story no exceptions
when the inner
the inner body of a plant an animal an
insect reaches over 120 degrees
death occurs
so another law on planet Earth Inc that
belongs to the biology of planet Earth
is actually that temperature range
so there's another reason why it makes
sense that humans
could learn from all the other creatures
on the planet and the plant life that in
order to keep ourselves alive
we might benefit from ingesting live
food
So to that also of course belongs
every creature and every plant has a
preferable range of nutrients and a
preferable source
for those nutrients right and
sorry I'm gonna
drink a little super drink
I've been talking too much
um
all of us have a particular
source of nutrients that we can best
absorb you can't feed a plant liquid
acid right or crude oil or and think
that why can't it draw the nutrients
from that crude oil you know I have
beautiful orchids in here let me pour
some crude oil on them it's a liquid it
is full of minerals and stuff
doesn't work why
in my lectures people will say because
it's not made for that because I train
them of course you know it's not made
for that so every plant every animal
needs a particular source of nutrients
to function well
and of course all of life functions by
having trillions of cells that are
actually individual entities if you will
but that are in the flow of life at all
times so some some scientists now say
there is no such thing as a cell because
as long as we're alive it's always in
mutation it's always in movement it's
always
decomposing recomposing new things but
if we just look at it like this model it
still helps us understand every cell
needs nutrients and constantly to to
produce
new cells or fulfill its function you
know add to the new liver cells add to
the lung cells create new blood cells
white blood cells red blood cells bone
cells blah blah blah blah all these
different cells are constantly recreated
so that our body is constantly new
if we don't provide the nutrients so
that the cell reproduction can continue
what happens
deterioration because the existing cells
cannot live long enough
so we have all this dead stuff in our
body if we don't provide the nutrients
to produce new cell tissue
and then wherever you have a weak spot
already or wherever the other toxicities
already that's where we then
decompose not recompose enough and we
get whatever it is the liver of failure
kidney failure lung diseases arthritis
in the joints migraines in the head
depending on where we already have weak
spots or where there's additional
toxicity impact
so
to me
life is quite simple
and logical
that providing the right nutrients for
the right species
at the right temperature should come
natural
and then of course when you compare the
human body again biology tells it all
if you compare the human body to other
creatures on the planet
who are we most similar to and we can
observe what those creatures eat
always are the monkeys
well we may not like
that we are similar in biology of course
we are similar in biology to all life on
planet Earth let me put that out there
too
you know we're just as similar to a pig
as we are to the monkey or almost
right so people joining us it's
wonderful
um
so that biology however has some
differences just as I said you can't
feed a plant crude oil you can't feed a
lion hey
try
I don't think that'll work and you can't
feed
a deer lion flesh
come on it's good nutrients lots of iron
and everything in there you know eat
that lion please my cow or my dear right
tend to why
why can't we
do that
because the physiology of the specific
creature is not made the lion cannot
break down the hay it does not have it's
multiple stomachs like a cow it does not
have the enzymes to break down hay plant
matter it requires that chunk of Flesh
that raw flesh that it tears out of the
prey
swallows it in large lumps has an
esophagus that opens wide to allow whole
lumps of Flesh and Bones and skin and
Hooves to go down the esophagus into the
stomach so then the carnivore has this
big lump of Flesh in the stomach what
then
being said
it what
that's it
acids that's the answer exactly it has
20 times dehydrochloric acid from
herbivores
and therefore it can actually dissolve
that flesh
and as you know hydrochloric acid is a
very very dangerous substance when used
on skin for example on the outside it
literally burns the skin it melts the
skin so it dissolves skin tissue bone
tissue Hooves everything
and we just don't have that
that's why we are not thrilled when
there is this road kill by the roadside
we don't stop we run out of there and
dig our teeth into that roadkill and
suck out the blood and like that
swallow it down will open our throat Etc
so again to me just
plain observation of nature tells us
what to do
and since we're almost similar to those
great apes and those wonderful
incredibly strong large creatures
in the digestive tract
it makes sense to claim that not just
claim to observe that we too indeed are
herbivores
yeah but we evolved because with cooked
food we can develop bigger brains and
with cooked food we can get more
nutrients
um
humans are evolved but but they humans
are smarter themselves
well humans may be able to think and are
smarter than cells but we don't change
the function of itself
[Music]
yeah yeah thank you exactly so we can we
can override but we can't really change
that biology in our stomach therefore we
have to cook and spice and chop into
little pieces or make it soft enough so
our our
our teeth can chew materials to break it
down before it goes into the stomach we
can't follow swallow a whole lump Etc so
um Laurie Owens there are some arguments
for you and your husband
to
to explain why
it makes sense to consume plant-based
foods and of course yes we do get
sufficient somewhat sufficient nutrients
from cooked foods but it is still
ingesting a lot of dead matter that
helps ourselves less than a little bit
of raw matter and I brought you
something just to water your mouth just
to get you excited you know this is a
chocolate mousse that is raw and super
delicious so just for you to know of
course there's also chocolate cake in
the freezer and there's pizza and
there's
pesto and lots of other things
so we don't have to
here's the difference we don't have to
stop being creative
to start being healthy
and of course I got to put a quick um
promo in here I just launched my app and
there is a course on my app I will put
the
uh the all the links in the chat in a
minute
um
relish's dishes in other words and you
can you can get those it's a whole slew
of 12 different super delicious dishes
um
because it doesn't mean that we have to
stop being creative when we realize that
we can eat the most nutrient dense foods
and that would be raw organic
um delicious foods so we can make the
same compositions just as I can make you
know lots of different chocolates with
with the ingredients that might might be
different from cooked ingredients in in
a cooked chocolate
but I have the the density of the new
the nutrients in this chocolate and I
have the delicious flavor and the
exuberance and now we get two why
celebrations matter
more people are joining us that is so
cool welcome everybody whom I haven't
welcomed individually
show your faces if you can
Hannah is here Monique is here Sandra is
here Arlen is here
Andrea is here Christine
and everybody else I introduced already
but welcome if you can show your faces
and
um however I'm in the middle of the
presentation now so I want to continue
with
um getting too healthy through the
holidays so you can learn those recipes
on my course on the app it's only forty
seven dollars so it's not like it used
to be you know we had to pay lots of
money for a course in recipes
um it's a video video course all right
what do we do then when it gets to
celebrations and we want to get together
with family and we want to really enjoy
and I maintain that celebrations and I
did a whole show about celebrations oh
and that's the other thing on my you get
more free content on my twitch Channel
twitch.tv Rossum life show
um again I'm going to put all of them in
in the chat
celebrations are also a unique uniquely
human feature as is creativity and of
course with creativity comes music
language actually the other way around
language but maybe music came first who
knows maybe people were just singing
sounds to each other before they
developed language and and articulate
things in words you know and then we
have dance and all the art forms and all
of humanity wherever I have been and
I've been on three continents in 39
countries
that is creativity everywhere it is a
human feature period
and creativity has been there in my book
ever since there have been humans on
planet Earth
not like people running around living in
caves with some baseball bat type of
thing
trying to chase down a rabbit yeah good
luck with that one
um
but um but yeah other scientists talk
about that now finally as well because
we're slowly overcoming
darwinistic Concepts because we think
that is actually science but it's a
story it's uh just like the Bible and
Adam and Eve it's another story that we
projected backwards because we live in a
world of thinking in a philosophy where
we need to believe that everything is
linear and ascending right ascending
means going upwards so humans were
stupid and now we're the most
intelligent ever right we have the best
ever
but with ways to go ways to go in
understanding and perceiving how the
world works so celebrations are part of
human expression of Being Human
so therefore it is very important that
we don't say well I just want to eat
carrots and celery sticks and
be healthy
I don't participate you know I shun my
relatives who eat all this junk no I say
turn that around
make incredibly beautiful delicious
dishes
and you know when you look at the kind
of stuff that I make
um
the visual impact is just as important
as is the Taste impact
so creating dishes that are beautiful
and great tasting and bringing them to
an event and having everybody share in
your healthy dishes
makes you the heart of the party
right makes you the celebrity and you
can always say well you know I eat crazy
sorry guys you know I I just I just want
to have fun with my life and this is the
way I can be happiest and healthiest
period you don't have to preach you
don't have to do anything but if you
bring a dish that everybody thinks oh my
God that's so pretty that is so
delicious Johanna
then you've got an entry into changing
the way people perceive you and perceive
the healthier way of eating as not being
restrictive but as being
indulging
ecstatic you know Zach Bush Dr Zach Bush
talks about that's when you realize that
life can be orgasmically ecstatic in all
essential experiences
and yes we're going through crazy times
where we notice
and I'm approaching it from that angle
intentionally we notice suddenly or more
and more that we are being manipulated
into belief systems and into behaviors
that we may not really like we are
forced to be medicated locked up do
things that we may not consider
the right thing to do
however
when you look back in history
what is a new phenomenon is not that
we're being manipulated what is a new
phenomenon is that we notice
and that is the coolest thing
with freaking finally noticing that
throughout the period of Empires
and who knows how long before thousands
of years
Empires the empirical structures really
started about
six seven thousand years ago in a bigger
way and where Planet wide it's an
interesting analysis when you look at
what kind of systems happened throughout
the world
then of course in any Empire has to
manipulate its populace
has to manage its populace has to keep
its populace down
so much so that you know this whole
delusion that people have oh but people
had their own little farm and their own
backyard and they ate their own stuff
that stuff wasn't owned by them either
it belonged to the king
and the King could decide any time okay
everybody bring me your bread or your
animals or your
um fruits because
I am sending whatever
thousands of soldiers into a war or
whatever the the goal was right or I am
trading all the stuff that you produced
shipping it from China to Rome and the
silk trades Etc because
that's what we're doing
we want to get whatever they have
in exchange so
I'm gonna close on
um
on that realization that the
collaboration of Commerce and governance
in Empire States
is as old as Empires
so when we today complain that
corporations Run the World
there is nothing new about that and the
collaboration between royalty and old
money and inheritance of money and new
money that had become super rich and
joined those circles
we can just look at the example of 1910
when the Rockefellers and
four or five other families set together
they owned combined they owned 51 or
more of of the entire oil discoveries at
the time and they decided right there
and then that we're going to make
everything out of oil and since food
didn't work medicine was definitely
going to work that's how we have our
medical system and everything else was
going to be considered hoaxes and that
goes back to 1910 so let's not have any
Illusions about this it's a new
Phenomenon with the medical industrial
complex that was created at that time
and of course it has built and it has
had more and more grasp but what's
really new is that we're becoming aware
it's phenomenal it's beautiful so all of
you if you want to learn you can
create your own life I in another show
of mine on Twitch I was talking about do
you own your body
do we own our own body have we ever
owned our body you know of course
there's the
um Whitney Webb's books just came out
Nation Under blackmail about the whole
Epstein story and how that leads back to
Global Powers
um using child
um
child sexual child trafficking and child
sexual abuse for black male in politics
Etc that too is thousands of years old
but not even as a crime but as a habit
habitually women and children were owned
by their fathers or husbands
and if a husband died the the wife was
going back either to a brother or back
to the father in terms of ownership we
are owned kids all children were owned
they could be sexually abused it's even
in Old Bibles
that fathers have the right to The
Virginity of their daughters or to the
sexual abuse of their boys as well a
colleague of mine when I studied
um world of education did her thesis on
that topic so she really went into all
these old Bibles and found that the text
is actually in there you can do this to
your children until they are of a
certain age at which time they're
considered
um
adults which at the time was like 13 14.
and can be sold into marriage or into
um
are given away
yeah or into slavery for that matter
so
let us not
think that going back to any
romanticized period is useful
but realizing that with this Awakening
with the realization that we have the
power to understand and to say I am a
human being full of self-healing
capacity now let's teach each other how
that works and how we can make it work
in this particular world because of
course we also cannot change this world
we cannot change
that we are at the state we're in that
the global situation is what it is but
we can change how we react to it
with it how we interact with each other
and how we create our own well-being so
that we can hook up with others who are
also on that path of self healing
um and again I'm going to now put
I'm going to give you five minutes to
maybe write down your question so that
we can go at them one after another and
I'm going to write in the text
the various
ways you can find more information
Twitch TV
um
I am on there Monday through Thursday
one to three PM Eastern Time
and
there's a and it's free you know unless
you want to become a paying member which
is five dollars a month or something
like that
awesome live show
no no what am I doing
some nice show
oh
and then there is the app is
raw some life
courses
dot passion
.io Rossum life courses.passion.io
I'm so bad at making typos so
and then of course there are
there is a super special offer
um yeah I just wanted to talk quickly
about the six things
that the six things that belong to a
healthy new lifestyle
and I'm gonna share screen for a minute
here
and they apply as to you know what you
need to think about or do in your life
to really create that full lifestyle
where you feel validated and
we should also talk about
monetizing because in this world we do
need money to pay our rent our mortgage
our car payment our food Etc so
monetizing your particular skills and
your abilities is also very important
and there are certain ways that some of
us have learned as to how to do that
and I'm happy to share
and share screen I'm slow
um
wait I need this
why is this not going over here do I
need to take it back over here
okay can you see
Johannes raw foods and coaching
the six step evolve system you had it
before I think Knight E1 I have awesome
chocolates now chilling
oh
you're seeing oh I see so you do see
that screen yeah yeah
so that's another thing that's at
Johannes raw food slash
[Music]
you can see it on the menu
um
so yeah so
just changing the food habit does not
quite cut it off of course it's a really
great start
but
in the very beginning I'm always asking
people who want to work with me or who
come to events you know ask yourself
why do I want to live
and people are like what do you mean
obviously I want to live
um but why
ask yourself why what do you want to do
with this lifetime
what's your contribution what's your
joyful and of course there's this thing
going around on the interwebs on on
social media you know well what do you
want to do with your life well I want to
be happy and you know they're these
answers that just drive home that Living
For Pleasure and happiness is good
enough is a wonderful thing
and I say that is true because true
happiness comes from
your contribution being validated so
that is the first question
clarify or explore and clarify what you
really want
that's the why question
um
next is verify the science and
experience that it works and that is
somehow somewhat you know what I just
told you about how biology works on
planet Earth so we can we can say verify
the science is
realizing that oh that's how it works
but you can also realize it once you've
done like a seven day smoothie cleanse
or a high cruciferous cleanse or
um
and dairy can Derry used to you're doing
the high cruciferous right
yes it's great
and there's just another level of that
high green content that empowers you in
so many ways so that's another way to
verify that it works that you experience
how wonderful it works and girls
beautiful thanks for sharing and then
there is
of course a lot of baggage that all of
us have so that's overcoming obstacles
as in
patterns that we've inherited from our
upbringing from our parents from our
genetic makeup Etc are very very hard to
override you can only override them for
so long they will always pop back up
when you're in a crisis situation right
so
overcome is not really the right word
my my mission is to say
um
hi Dinah my mission is to say transform
your trauma into tools
because everything you have ever
experienced on planet Earth
can be used for better understanding of
how the world works for better
understanding others who are suffering
for
being reminded of
how not to be
when you want to start a new life so
turn your traumas into tools is a very
very important step
and then we come to to loving our bodies
I mean many people have said you know
you got to love yourself you got to love
your body but I really mean literally
stand in front of the mirror and say to
yourself love I love my body
now
that also empowers you to say I'm going
to shape it as I want
so that's when you know your exercise
program your meditation your breathing I
do the Wim Huff method love it and
lots of other modalities but especially
exercise
um will help you shape that body the way
you want it but you can't do that when
you don't love it you have to love it
you have to empower it to say I know
that you're in there you super body that
I have and want and then you go to work
at it it's not going to happen by itself
so love your body then we have a step at
which we feel okay now I am perfectly
fine and all these other morons out
there you know that's just their fault
that they're just not getting it
that's not a healthy or happy way to be
either
so once your own Vitality is
sufficiently established your self-love
is there it is incumbent upon you to
begin to share and mix and that's again
where celebrations become so important
that you bring yourself your Healthy
self your super food and share not
preaching just sharing and hearing other
people's stories why they're not there
maybe carefully when asked suggests that
they could try something
so that's the last part of the six steps
namely socializing yourself and
re-socializing yourself even with groups
that are not there you also need the
groups that are supportive of the way
your new lifestyle works but you also
want to be strong enough to mix wherever
you are with regular
folks
um I'm laughing because just a couple of
nights ago a girlfriend invited me to
this concert at this old church
you know and there were all these
regular people
uh why am I having an echo suddenly
that's really weird
all right so that's enough of this
sharing let me stop sharing
all right and
that program I teach in my 12-month
program it's called the super happy body
program because healthy is not enough it
also needs to be happy and it needs to
provide happiness and understanding
which again is linked if we don't
understand diddly
I think oh somebody has the speaker on
so we get a feedback
um
we
we don't want to call ignorance Bliss is
what I was going to say
um because I speak around
unmute
[Music]
yeah I mean is it is it annoying
elsewhere
is it gone now it seems it's gone right
it's okay it's okay on our end
yeah
yeah Dairy has his
but I don't hear any feedback anymore if
you do let me know so in other words
ignorance is not Bliss and in fact
unfortunately in today's world ignorance
causes a lot of suffering because we
blindly walk into the manipulation that
I've been talking about right
and
it does not help
I'm really annoyed with the fact that I
don't have any light
so
I feel like I should light out my face
and I have all these devices and for
some reason I didn't set this up right
okay now we get to the Q a part and I'd
really love to get your questions
you can just unmute yourself we're not
that many
this is really nice Johanna I have to
leave now but thank you so much
cool you're so welcome
keep it up with the cruciferous so I uh
if you want to share what has it changed
for you to go cruciferous
a high cruciferous I should say yes
um
just a little more I think just feeling
more
um I feel stronger
and um where I was feeling a lot weaker
before
a lot more energy a little more clarity
in my thinking
it's been um
I feel like I am the things I've been
trying to heal is getting better
through his parts of my body
so it's kind of it's not a holistic all
over
um beneficial for me
yeah I do it all day I I do greens and
fruit vegetables and things like that
it's really great yeah wonderful thank
you so much for sharing so sometimes
even though we already think we are in a
very healthy diet when we have crisis
and we all do by the way I have crises
as well because there are other stresses
that impact on our health there's an
electromagnetic fields there's
um there's toxicity in the air there's
you know of course we're all driving
cars through traffic
Etc et cetera so there's lots of other
things and there's stress
stress produces a lot of toxicity in our
body
I don't know if it's out
all right
anybody else
yes
um
so one of my Doula clients
um I'm thinking about her specifically
um do you have a specific cleansing
protocol for nursing mothers
one of my clients is removing all the
toxins including mold from her
environment she also wants to do a
cleanse to combat skin cancer as she's
nursing an infant she needs to find a
protocol that won't release too many
toxins in her breast milk
yeah I don't think when you switch to a
raw High green diet and when you're
nursing obviously you need more fats
than other people need so include
sunflower seeds flax seeds
chia seeds
and
um
walnuts those are all omega-3 dense
um fatty acid providing Foods including
those with high green both Savory and
sweet meaning fruit and greens mixes
you can
flush out toxins and I I've maintained
that smoothies in this case are better
than juices because smoothies include
the fiber and that cleanses the
intestinal attract gently
it's not a sudden shock a sudden switch
to
um something very different like juicing
can Infuse a lot of nutrients directly
into the bloodstream but it doesn't give
the full effect of
yeah what what a plant includes and
that's always large amounts of fiber
which I think are necessary and I think
in
breastfeeding mothers there needs to be
enough fat
and it should not be animal fat of any
kind
um a little story quickly to that when I
worked at the international law firm a
colleague of mine a young lawyer had a
baby and and the baby had terrap she
looked like she hadn't slept in weeks
um the baby had terrible stomach colics
um
colleagues are by definition of course
stomach cramps
um and she she said to me do you have
any can I do anything and yes I'm going
to go get my light too as you just did
um
and I said try
to go Leave Out All Jerry
and our animal products just for two
weeks and she said okay I need to ask my
doctor about that and so I said okay ask
your doctor I'll give you some recipes
Etc to make sure that there's enough raw
in there as well
and
her doctor was wise enough to say well
you know since we haven't figured out
what to do with your cramping baby why
don't you try it
and she came back
less than two weeks later and said
Johanna I have a new baby you would not
recognize him and at first I thought oh
is she pregnant again what's up
she said no my child sleeps my child
laughs my child has not had a single
cramp
and then of course I told her that I had
found studies in Scandinavia where
colicky babies had been tested had been
taken off Dairy
um again for a short period of time and
80 percent of all colleagues even the
most severe went away now of course
there are some situations where there is
physical
impairment of the intestinal tract so
that there is
difficulty and digestion okay so just a
moment so now we're talking about babies
drinking or eating dairy products
directly no the mothers
my mother's diet yes in in this case
because you know that's we like you said
you know I wanted to say earlier you
know when uh when you are eating the
foods that are not made for you you know
um breast milk is is the species
specific food absolutely it is exactly
what the baby needs yeah but if the
mother ingests stuff that the baby
doesn't need of course it goes directly
into the breast milk
yeah yeah after the Chernobyl um
accident with the nuclear plant
imploding there and and all the toxicity
all of Europe was prohibited to to
breastfeed
because the they were nuclear fallout
concentrates in the breasts and I'm
gonna go get my light
okay
um yeah I can hear everybody yes
so in the meantime I want to thank you
for confirming what I intuitively
already thought that uh it would be
great for her to just um do smoothies
and um get the facts going and it's
really important that she gets all the
right fats like you mentioned the flash
she uh
um what else did you mention
um Walnut no animal products sunflower
seeds right yes um
so pumpkin seed is another good one I
think
um yes I I I don't know why but I've
never used my pumpkin seeds but I
actually like them in products yeah you
can get them yeah May there be light
hello
I am here yes so and then Super greens
of course and what do you think of
um seaweed
see it is very very good I just
personally have never developed much of
a taste for the seaweed salad and that
stuff that you know became so popular so
I try to put some kelp into my smoothies
sometimes and into my burgers and other
things so no it's very very good make
sure that it comes from a I mean get it
get your seaweed in a health food store
because it's less likely to be
glyphosate and other exposures of course
unfortunately
85 percent of all our waters on the
entire planet
is contaminated 85 of all our Waters
oceans rivers lakes everything rain
water
so we got a lot of work to do to clean
up the mess because it's not really
about
the climate change from cars it's about
the toxicity put out there with the
glyphosates and the fertilizers and the
herbicides and the
and the teflons and the Plastics Etc
throughout the planet for the last
hundred years so I I want to mention
that you know there are studies that
have been done
um that shows that the Japanese seaweed
uh you know after the exposure to the
tsunami and then the nuclear waste from
the nuclear power plants
um they actually those seaweeds from
Japan are the most
um the most effective in the removal of
radiation nuclear radiation amazingly
and not amazingly because
um Earth is self-cleansing as are all
the bodies that that's again it's a
biology it's a
you know yes it's ironic because of
course
plant life adapts amazing we are we're
really self-cleansing like you know the
worst thing we can do is especially on
our intimate body parts uh use soap it's
the worst thing we can do actually
yes
much more so much more to that water
just you know make sure you have clean
water and use that yes there's so much
more to of course the industrialization
the we today and and I did not talk
about that but it's on my
um agenda
we have in addition to what we produce
we ourselves have become the product for
corporate interests we are the pr the
product by way of having us consume
constantly and of course by way of
grafting our data and using that to make
us more of a product to make us more
dependent to make us and then of course
transhumanism and all those Concepts so
but with the beginning of awareness
you know please please everybody connect
connect connect let us work together
let's see where things fit
um
Regina is here and Nellis here from the
rossumlife global.com online university
we are not funded yet to really launch
but we're working on that and the more
people become aware
um the better we better chance we have
to get launched also again for you Lori
you were asking about you know going on
to other platforms
um
it is important that we create awareness
wherever
people have not been reached yet but are
possibly
able to awaken it's very very hard for
people to realize oops I made a mistake
but if we
if we tell the story as it actually is
oh Humanity has always fallen for all
these ruses for all these stories for
these narratives that you know oh we're
only
plundering the rest of the world in
colonialism because we're civilizing the
Savages right those with this narratives
told at home
that's right and they and and the use of
mercury even my husband he grew up in
Morocco and they were still using uh
besides iodine they were using some form
of mercury for wound care yes because it
was used as an antibiotic it was used as
a medicine very toxic yeah of course but
I mean antibiotic is in and of itself of
course the definition of anti-life it
kills so all antibiotics are killers of
life so it's not really I used to call
cayenne pepper Ginger
um
raw honey and garlic and other such
remedies ginseng I used to call them
natural antibiotics but they're actually
not antibiotics they do not kill life
they rebalance
yeah they actually rebalance and help
cleanse out the toxins so I I revise
myself sometimes in those areas that
um
that we have to really look at very
closely yeah so
all right everybody Dinah Linda Rouser
Monique
Arlen Andrea
Christine Ed
was Dev Shirley Valerie Susan Boyce
Regina
and Lori
come on bring It
Regina has a question um I can read it
unless you want to say it yourself
Regina did I miss it
it says uh thank you so much are your
recipes also for people with diabetes oh
absolutely thank you for asking
absolutely now diabetes you know I say
all chronic diseases
um can be healed
in weeks or days sometimes
while it took decades for the body to
accumulate so much toxicity to present
as that
um that chronic disease
putting somebody on a raw food diet
there's a wonderful movie that's still
around called 30 days on Raw
um Dr
um
ah my dear
my dear friend sometimes Gabriel cousins
um is at the center of it and you know
there's six people coming from all walks
of life severely diabetic and within 10
days even the most severe one is off all
medication off uh
ailments you know and then they just
learn how to live a healthier life so
all organic raw foods automatically take
you off of diabetes now if you want to
include some cooked foods that can be
done it just takes a little longer Dr
esselstin for example with Whole Food
plant-based now does it in three months
I'm just saying you know Wise people
hello
yeah Dr Gabriel cousins
um that but that movie is still on
YouTube you can find it
um free uh simply raw reversing diabetes
in 30 days
um
why not go raw when you can do it that
much faster
you can then add in some cooked food but
you know at least you have that
experience how it works or experience
that it works because once you've done
even just a five day smoothie cleanse
you have experienced the power
of raw healing
and of course while
some of my colleagues like like Dr
Brooke goldner will say just get started
I don't care if it's not organic just
get started with the green smoothies
amen of course you you still putting a
lot of toxins back into your body when
the plants are not organically grown and
because the packaging is another step at
which
vegetables can get very contaminated
even if the GMO free
or non-GMO
um
same cure and your daughter has thyroid
thyroid nodules
um the size as long as you still have a
piece of thyroid even if some of it has
been cut out the thyroid will regenerate
and I learned this you know a couple of
decades ago at a workshop for or at I
was actually providing food there too so
I was working but it was presented that
that thyroid
regrows and
Finds Its full function because of
course it's a very important hormone
producer
um
when you go on raw food
for even just a period of time
um and again you can probably do it with
Whole Food plant-based low you know no
no oil that kind of thing that again SL
stands do
foreign
but it's just so much faster and so much
easier and you know I can help people
with the delicious recipes that also
make it a incredibly delicious
experience you know when healing becomes
delicious
then we get away from this whole concept
of disease and now I have to eat all
these horrible medicines that taste
horrible and whatever I have other side
effects and so forth yeah like it's not
like it's a chore suddenly right exactly
like it's a chore like it's a punishment
you know to to heal from something when
you make the healing process itself into
a celebration
what's there to complain about right
well you can have your body celebrate as
well I found that to be true when I
first tasted your raw food back in
Oneonta when you used to live there and
you introduced your raw foods at the
health food store 10 years ago yeah and
um so the first time I tasted uh
johanna's food I literally just went I
never had a blood transfusion but I bet
it would feel like this
I don't know what that little
transfusion well not these days you know
from a healthy person perhaps but
um
um I feel really like literally just all
of my my bodily fluids came back to life
that's really what it felt like yeah and
that's why that's why step two in this
six step program that I teach is verify
that it works verify the science and
verify that it works experience that it
works it it you can't replace that with
all the stories that I can tell you you
can't replace that experience of oh my
God I haven't had a headache in three
days that has never happened in years oh
my God I actually slept and didn't have
to go to the bathroom my doctor told me
that my liver failure was fatal and you
know I have so many months to live
I've had it in my own experience with my
clients so there's just nothing like
allowing a person to have that
experience
yeah
yeah I I went wrong you know I've gone
raw a few times you know off and on in
different times I know the the last time
I did it
it was such an incredible
electrical feeling of connection with my
brain and a like a mental
experience of life and and and and the
the desire for life and the the quest it
was it was an amazing thing the the the
the enzymes the the energy the the uh
you know it's got to be something
electrical that connects you know thank
you thank you for taking us there Lori
so true you know when I always say the
more you know the more you know how
little you know that is an area of of
understanding that we haven't even
touched on that is the fact that life is
energy everything we experience and and
have and do is energy and how does
everything we put into our body change
the entire energetic
interaction of everything
so Energy Medicine and understanding
what is energy is definitely one of the
next level
um of research and understanding however
since corporate Station corporate
entities have not figured out how to
make money on that
it's just not favored right now I mean
Einstein came to the conclusion
everything is energy and many before him
but yeah since we are product driven
um and let me just quickly talk about
and of course we live in a product
driven world that's why we also and
those of you who are interested in
learning how to monetize your particular
skill in helping others get well or
helping others become coaches or helping
others be
moving Humanity forward
um again connect with me to
learn some of the modalities that how we
can use the existing
Technologies even because I mean we're
talking to each other because of
Technology right so using what is to the
benefit of better understanding better
health a better self-healing Planet
healing Etc
can be very rewarding and of course is
really where it's at so if we all want
to move Humanity forward
we can learn those modalities of how to
monetize so that we can again function
in this world because as much as we
might want to Homestead somewhere on a
piece of land
we'd still have to pay taxes to somebody
ah
so because every little piece of the
planet in today's reality is owned
you can eat more when you go raw you can
actually eat more food and not worry
oh definitely well the thing is I mean
some people especially fruitarians eat a
lot of fruit right A lot of it I find
that my portions are rather small
because I'm so full because it's such
nutrient dense stuff
like what do I have here I have here a
pesto
and a hazelnut lentil Burger sprouted
lentils and hazelnuts and a couple of
baby Tomatoes this little thing here is
a meal
you know and then of course I have this
and that will be
how much how much cocoa is in that
mousse I mean that's how like from the
cacao powder that's a lot of cacao there
isn't it that's cacao yeah you're not
gonna sleep tonight if you eat all that
[Laughter]
oh to me
and many of my colleagues raw cacao does
not have the effect of coffee which you
know some people of course it does have
a caffeine related compound in it CYO
bromine
um which
revitalizes the the body and provides a
lot of magnesium potassium calcium iron
and manganese so
if you don't have a need for those
things which I seem to always have I
always have a need for those things so
I'm good with a lot of cacao I can go
right to sleep after eating cacao but I
do have friends who cannot
um
um like my
my colleague and dear friend Karen
Ramsey
uh feel fabulous with Foods
will um yeah she will not eat anything
with chocolate after lunch because she
says I can't sleep so I I've never had
that experience which means my body
obviously does well but I also I work
hot I work out hard or I run or I just
now be like I said before this this
Mastermind I just ran up the hill near
me it's not very much it's just two
miles but still
you know so I'm I'm in motion and I
challenge my muscle tissue which is
naturally not very good I was born with
really poor tissue and a hole in my
heart and all sorts of other issues so I
can handle
I need a lot of work out and I can
handle a lot of raw cacao and stuff that
other products that give me particularly
potassium and magnesium which I seem to
need a lot for example I make root
mushes with um
with celeriac celery root and
um
and what's the other one the sweet one
I'll help me out here and turmeric no
turmeric is very spicy
um I just bought some raw turmeric it's
it was I ate I ate a whole thing it was
good just I just ate it raw it was not
spicy
turmeric no I mean it had a little bite
to it but it was uh yeah I ate it
okay cool
um
parsnip yes yes Ireland that was parsnip
absolutely so celeriac and parsnip and
you know you can throw beets in there or
beat Greens in there so I make these
these thick mushes with also with nuts
either walnuts or cashew nuts and or
some cauliflower thrown in so they're
like mashed potatoes but it's just those
rude vegetables with a little bit of
fruit like half a half an orange goes in
there and then spices
but that is like real potassium dense
food and I seem to need a lot of that
too especially after hard workouts when
those muscles need to like okay now we
can relax you know just keep growing or
keep maintaining so yeah it's uh
it's definitely different for different
people but
I don't know I've never had an issue
with raw cacao
and again tell me if anybody else here
has an issue with raw cacao keeping you
awake
uh you know I just I just I just eat it
earlier in the day in the afternoon I
you know I don't really eat it before I
go to bed as a rule so
yeah
which is fine
now of course this has a lot of other
stuff in it just to give you a quick
rundown this has fresh pears banana so
pear banana frozen strawberries frozen
raspberries raisins dates
um
apricots very iron rich again apricots
in particular
um
then almonds I used almonds this time
instead of often walnuts and cashews
um almonds
a little bit of coconut virgin coconut
oil just to give it that smoothness a
little bit of cacao butter
and then a few drops of vanilla essence
a couple of grains of Celtic Sea salt
and the raw cacao
so it's a lot of stuff you know so the
cacao is just one of the 10 ingredients
that are in here but of course the cacao
creates the flavor the most you can
still taste if you have a fine taste
buds
you can still taste the banana and then
all the other good stuff so
but I'm pointing that out of course you
know for some people like I have a
client who has just
uh
gone away from all sweet fruits and and
things and is finding that it helps her
a lot
um to not ever have migraines but it's
mostly psychological in her case so we
work on actually she doesn't have
migraines anymore but she used to have
and she's still afraid that she'll get
them
um
so it's different for everybody and
people who have found that eating
non-sweet in the majority of you know
maybe doing very well too now I
maintained that of course the brain
needs glucose and fat
and again cell reproduction needs
essential fatty acids because the cell
membrane this
is made of essential fatty acids so that
is a necessary ingredient that if we
deprive ourselves we may just go a
little duller in the brain I don't know
whether that's true but you know I'm
just projecting here
so good fats and good sugars are
actually energy providers and brain
enhancers that's why you know people
like
um Doug Graham Dr duck Graham who is
frutarian for the most part so he eats a
little bit of greens
um but he works out four hours a day and
he trains athletes so you know he burns
of course all that sugar so I for me
that wouldn't be a good idea because I
don't work out that much I don't burn
that much sugar
um and I but I also don't want to go the
other way where there is no sweet
fruit
stuff
because I feel I need that push that
energy push
all right
so is anybody
interested anybody who's new here whom I
don't know Barbara Sandoval Dina Anthony
Monica Roche Arlen Baden
um who else do I not know Ed
don't know you very well
um and Dev
and Valerie Frankie
and Susan Susan Boyce we've talked
before I have the feeling
um
is anybody wanting to take advantage of
this super offer that is currently back
up it still says Black Friday offer but
I just said okay let's put that back up
for these shows so that you can take
advantage with my 12-month program
instead of eight thousand dollars is
available for three thousand dollars or
297 a month so that's incredible
um but I if anybody wants to take
advantage of that please email me or
um put it in the in the chat
how much is the cruciferous
uh what is it a smoothie I don't know
smoothie cleanse
um
yeah is
the person who does it most even though
I've I've always done it but not to the
extreme enough tried it now to the to
the more extreme is Dr Brooke goldner
oh and and
um she started it to heal people from
lupus she cured herself from or rather
her husband
um had that idea and then they developed
this whole program and now all all um
autoimmune diseases and arthritis Etc
you can again you know but it's the same
thing you go raw and high cruciferous
speeds up that energy provider
and
um cleansing element
and in in her research it turned out to
be the most nutrient dense food you can
put into your body and that's
cruciferous green vegetables and you
know there's a whole bunch of them
combined with she combines it with a
little bit of fruit I also combine it as
I call it gazpacho smoothie with garlic
and ginger and spices and cucumber in it
and so forth so it becomes this like
oh very very delicious
better than salad in a soup kind of
thing
so
so yeah you can cruciferous is
definitely yet another level wonderful I
wonder if I made this
okay yeah you said that video for the um
healing diabetes was what
simply Raw
I think you may have seen it Christine
Maybe
simply
Raw
reversing okay
diabetes
in
30 days
abuse in 30 days yeah
oh
all right my dear people I've also I've
also heard that there's something in um
napalm
Napalm uh Cactus that's really good for
diabetics
Napalm I only know Napalm as that
terrible Atari burning stuff that they
poured on people in Vietnam no no sweet
at the Spanish it's it's a it's a cactus
the green with the little thorns on it
okay can you pronounce it Spanish
Napalm and a Nopal no it's not Napalm
it's um it's what the cactus Leaf are
you talking about the cactus leaf
it's nopales
nopales yes
yes delicious
so um
what is good about Nopal
well I've heard you know that it's uh
it's it has properties in it to balance
your blood sugar to help people with
diabetic right I mean
I know a lot of things about different
things but I don't want to share them
all because it's not my show here but
you know I mean diabetes can be healed
oh but but Lori The crucial part is
always you can add something like a good
element like a good supposedly medicinal
plant but it will not override your
steak or your hot dog and as or even if
you do the the healing modality for two
weeks and go back to the old ways of
eating
it cannot last you will get sick again
so you have to change the lifestyle of a
person for them to remain healthy
especially diabetics you cannot possibly
fix it with medicine while not changing
your lifestyle
make sense
so therefore it is absolutely crucial
that that's why I went through all this
biology on planet Earth thing Etc
because if you don't understand the
basic functioning of human of the human
body and the health self-healing
modality you can take all the remedies
supplements remedies supplements and
medicines in the world it will not
override your steak or your egg for that
matter
because
your body will just collapse back into
the disease
so
change your lifestyle and of course you
can do that by yourself it just requires
quite a lot of discipline and research
to make that work for you so that you
can have a happy life and not feel
deprived and also not just say but I'm
taking my multivitamin pill sets when I
was in my teenage years you know a
multivitamin pills were like the thing
everybody thought okay pop a cup of
vital I took three of my multivitamins
this morning I'm good you know and then
here you go and eat your egg big egg and
bags yeah bacon and eggs
and yeah so we're gonna we're gonna say
goodbye
and thank you for being here thank you
for sharing thank you for checking out
what I've proposed you check out
um
I look forward to seeing you all in
different contexts or on other hi
Christine cool great to see you
um
I I look forward to seeing y'all
wherever next we cross paths or in the
next Mastermind I hope you got something
out of it that you can Implement in your
life and I hope that I see you on my
free content on the twitch.tv
slash Rawson live show
um lots of different topics all relating
to humanity on planet Earth uh discussed
there
the the show has three parts food no
Fitness food Humanity so we actually do
Fitness if you need a program to follow
you know I do my fitness live on the
channel
all right
everybody last words
ciao
love and light yes
thank you
thank you thank you
thank you thank you yeah who's speaking
everybody is just chiming in to say
thank you Joanna thank you that is so
lovely thank you thank you for being
here
and until next time Lori and if you want
some more talk about how to gently
convert your husband
talk to me
happy to
happy to help
thank you all right Andrea thank you
thank you you're welcome Andrea
and hi everyone
bye bye
bye
it's time to go to bed in Germany
sweet dreams
bye Shirley bye Susan